# PRANITH KUMAR GOURISETTY

+919908780080 | pranith.gourishetty@gmail.com | LinkedIn

### **SUMMARY**

Data Scientist with 5.2 years of experience in statistical and machine learning algorithms in solving business problems. Expertise in Python, R, SQL, Git, Data Preparation, Data Cleaning, Data Visualization, Data Modelling, Validation, and Power BI. Very strong in problem-solving using data structures and algorithms.

#### **SKILLS**

Technical: Python, R, SQL, Spark, Power BI

Cloud Service: Databricks, Azure

**Algorithms:** Linear and Logistic Regression • Random Forest • NLP • CNN • SVM • Time Series Forecasting **Packages:** Pandas • Numpy • Scikit-learn • Tesseract • TensorFlow • OpenCV • matplotlib • seaborn • nltk

Web Framework: Django, Flask, Rshiny(app)

## **EXPERIENCE**

## ARCADIS - Data Scientist - Hyderabad, India

Feb 2019 - Present

## **Architectural Drawing:**

- Extracting useful information from different Architectural Drawings from thousands of PDFs and creating a database for insights. Saved 90% of efforts to the business.
- Converting the PDFs to images and developed a deep learning model to extract the Region of Interest from the individual image. Preprocessing the Image and apply OCR(Tesseract) to extract the text from an image.

### **Road Condition Prediction:**

- Predicting the condition of a road for London, UK. To suggest the best possible time to do maintenance activity, which will
  reduce the cost of maintenance.
- Developed a Regression model to predict the road condition index for 3 years with better accuracy (RMSE).
- Built a web application to show the features impacting the road condition prediction values.

## **Technical Due Diligence**

- Developed a Machine learning model for predicting the Capital expenditure of an asset by using basic details of property without inspecting internally, which will reduce both the time by more than 16 hours and cost by 60% done by external agents.
- Extracted the information from multiple tables in a database using SQL to get the final usable data.
- Developed an API for getting the prediction results using the Flask framework.

#### ADP - Senior Member Technical - Hyderabad, India

Nov 2016 - Feb 2019

## **AutoPay – 401K Retirement Plans:**

- Extracting the Data and applying the preprocessing techniques.
- Continuous discussion with a Business analyst for a good understanding of the business problem and creating feature engineering.
- Applying machine learning algorithms and predicting the business outcome.
- Developed an automation script to clear the errors generated by the system which reduced the effort of manual testers and contribute to 28% of total errors

## WFN - Insights:

- Providing different insights from data like the Attrition rate, Over time, Performance, etc.
- Developed Power BI to project the insights.

## CAPGEMINI – Senior Software Engineer – Hyderabad, India

Sept 2014 - Nov 2016

## SSS:

- Design and developed application interface with an HP Test Automation Framework (UFT) in VB Script. Experienced in "Functional Testing" and "Regression Testing"
- Developed Automation script to compare the multiple tables in the database by using web services which decreased manual efforts by 18 hours for a single iteration.
- Involved in end-to-end automation project inclusive of planning, effort, design, scope, estimation, resource coordination, and delivery as per specified time frames in an Agile Environment.

# **CERTIFICATIONS**

PGP Certification in Big Data Analytics and Optimization – INSOFE

# **EDUCATION**

OSMANIA UNIVERSITY – Hyderabad, India

Bachelor of Engineering – Mechanical Engineering

June 2014